Cyber Security & Digital Forensics Undergraduate

Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, India LinkedIn: @<u>saketupadhyay</u> Twitter: :@<u>x64mayhem</u>

saketupadhyay@protonmail.com saketupadhya@gmail.com https://saket-upadhyay.github.io

Saket Upadhyay

Personal Profile

Research and Result oriented cybersecurity student.

Likes to experiment with different concepts and import strategies from exotic domains into cybersecurity.

Also, likes to learn new languages and meet different people.

Interests

- Malware Analysis, Structure and Deployment Strategies
- · Nature Inspired Cybersecurity
- Adaptive Cyber Defense Systems
- Android Security
- Cyber Physical Systems

Academic Background

Vellore Institute of Technology

B.Tech. in Computer Science with specialisation in Cyber Security and Digital Forensics

2018 - 2022

GPA (till 4/8 sem.): 8.25/10

Kendriya Vidyalaya

High School

2018

- Mathematics, Chemistry, Physics and Computer Science.
- First Class

Work Experience

RESEARCH INTERN

Renault Nissan Technical Business Center India (RNTBCI)

June 2020 - August 2020

 Advance Cybersecurity Concepts in Connected Autonomous Vehicles

PENETRATION TESTER (INTERN)

Azure Skynet Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

- TEST 5 ISOLATED SYSTEMS FOR VULNERABILITIES
- CREATE PoC
- CREATE VULNERABILITY REPORT
- PATCH FOUND VULNERABILITIES

Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, India LinkedIn: @<u>saketupadhyay</u> Twitter: @x64mayhem

saketupadhyay@protonmail.com https://saket-upadhyay.github.io saketupadhya@gmail.com

Misc. Experience

PolyX Malware Research Community Member

July 2020 - ongoing

• Active Member since July 2020. | PolySwarm

Student Organising Committee (FDP)

July 2020

• International Faculty Development Program | VIT

Organizing Committee

June 2020

• CyVIT'20 Cybersecurity Conclave | VIT

Student Organizing Committee

December 2019

• 19th International Conference on Hybrid Intelligent Systems | MIR LABS, VIT

Student Organizing Committee

December 2019

• 15th International Conference on Information Assurance and Security | MIR

Technical Lead

April 2019

• CyVIT'19 Cybersecurity Conclave | VIT

Publications

PACER: Platform for Android Malware Classification, Performance Evaluation and Threat Reporting

APR 2020 | Future Internet, MDPI

• https://doi.org/10.3390/fi12040066

PACE: Platform for Android Malware Classification and **Performance Evaluation**

DEC 2019 | IEEE International Conference on Big Data

- https://doi.org/10.1109/BigData47090.2019.9006557
- Best Paper Award

Patent

System and Method for **Characterization of External Memory Devices**

2020 | Intellectual Property India, Govt. of India (Published)

Talks

Malware Hunting with Machine Learning

2020 | Penn State World Campus Tech Club, Penn State, Pennsylvania

PACE: Paper Presentation, IEEE

2019 | International Conference on Big Data 2019, Los Angeles

Malware Detection and Classification

2019 | 15th International Conference on Information Security and Assurance, VIT

Cyber Security & Digital Forensics Undergraduate

Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, India LinkedIn: <u>@saketupadhyay.</u> Twitter : <u>@x64mayhem</u>

saketupadhyay@protonmail.com saketupadhya@gmail.com https://saket-upadhyay.github.io

Saket Upadhyay

Honors and Awards

Best Paper Award, IEEE

2019 | International Conference on Big Data 2019

1st Rank in DEFCON28 Secure Code Tournament

2020 | DEF CON 28 [SafeMode], SCW

1st Rank in DevSecCon24 Coding Tournament

2020 | Development Security Conference 24 (Singapore, Virtual Event)

Winner HackCoVIT'20 National Hack-a-thon

2020 | Information Security domain [India]

1st Rank in DerpCon 2020 SCW Tournament

2020 | Denver Enterprise Risk Professionals Conference 2020

Projects

NS3- Cybersecurity Simulations

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

SAMPARK: Website Connection Security Scanner

May 2020 - Jun. 2020

Android Device Threat Report Generation using PACE framework and ADB

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020 (Research Project)

PACE : Platform for Android application Classification and Evaluation

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019 (Research Project)

Live Movement Tracing in Android by using Polygraph lines.

Dec. 2018 - Mar. 2019

Certifications

Autopsy 8-Hour Online Training

APR 2020 | Basis Technology (ID - 16976888)

Fundamentals of Cyber Risk Management Public Version

APR 2020 | Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA)

Identifying Security Vulnerabilities in C/C++Programming

APR 2020 | University of California, Davis (Coursera)

Software Security

FEB 2020 | University of Maryland (Coursera)

Malware Threats

MAY 2019 | Cybrary (C-fbe069fd0-16d03e67a)

Advanced Penetration Testing

JAN 2018 | Cybrary (C-fbe069fd0-117bb4)

Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, India LinkedIn: @<u>saketupadhyay</u> Twitter: @x64mayhem

saketupadhyay@protonmail.com saketupadhya@gmail.com

Technical Skills

- Malware Analysis
- Reverse Engineering
- Vulnerability Assessment & Reporting
- Penetration Testing
- Technical Writing
- Secure Code Analysis

Languages and Technologies

- Assembly (x32, x64)
- C
- C++
- Python
- Java
- Android(Java based)
- Ruby

- Metasploit Framework
- **Brup Suite**
- Maltego
- Ida
- X32/X64 Debugger
- Ghidra
- GNU Debugger (Gdb)

Communication Languages

Hindi

(Native Proficiency) (Academic & Professional Proficiency) English

Russian (Elementary Proficiency)

Character Reference

Dr. Shishir Kumar Shandilya

Division Head, Cyber Security and Digital Forensics Division, VIT Bhopal Email: shishirkumar.s@vitbhopal.ac.in

Dr. Ajit Kumar

Post Doc. Researcher, Soongsil University, Seoul, South Korea Email: kumar@ssu.ac.kr

Dr. Neal Wagner

Complex Systems Scientist, Systems and Technology Research Analysis and Decision Systems Group Woburn, MA USA Email: neal.wagner@stresearch.com

Dr. Ayush Goyal

Assistant Professor, Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Texas A&M University Email: ayush.goyal@tamuk.edu